So let's get started with programming, and programming is really the core computer science.
让我们开始编程 编程是计算机科学的核心
Most machines are designed to do just one thing.
大多数的机械都是设计成只能做一件事的
This is supposed to be a toaster, more of a representational drawing than an accurate one.
这是一个烤面包机 只是大概的画一下 并不准确
And a toaster, we can do more than one thing with a toaster.
我们可以用一个烤面包机做好几件事
We can put different things in it. We can toast bread, we can toast muffins, maybe it has some things we can use to change its behavior a little bit.
我们可以把许多东西放进去 可以烤面包、做松饼 或许我们可以稍稍改动一下它
We can turn a setting to make it toast for longer or shorter.
我们可以使面包机烤的时间长些或短些
But it's pretty limited in what it can do. Everything it can do is a variation on this basic functionality that it was designed for:
但是我们能做的事情还是有限制的 所有的变化都是基于最基础的设计意图：
this basic process of putting toast in, heating it up and getting the toast to pop out.
把面包放进去 加热 然后等待面包从机器里蹦跶出来
If we want to change its behavior to do something really different, we'd have to physically alter the machine.
如果我们想要面包机的行为变得不同 我们必须从物理结构上改变这个机器
We could maybe take the parts out, and put them together in a new way.
我们或许可以取出部分零件 再把它们重新组装起来
If we're really creative we could make a bicycle from the toaster. That would be a pretty big project, though.
如果我们特别有创造力 说不定可以用烤面包机做个自行车 特别酷炫 但肯定挺复杂
So without a program a computer is even less useful than a toaster.
所以 如果没有了程序 电脑可能比烤面包机还要没用
The program is what tells the computer what to do.
是程序告诉了电脑去做什么
And the power of the computer, is that, unlike a toaster, which is only designed to do a few things, a computer can do anything.
电脑的厉害之处是 不像面包机那样只能做一些事 电脑可以做任何事
A computer is a universal machine. We can program it to do essentially any computation.
一台电脑是一台通用机 通过编程 我们可以让它做几乎任何计算
And what the program needs to be is a very precise sequence of steps.
而这个程序就是一系列精确的步骤
The computer by itself doesn't know how to do anything. It has a few simple instructions that it can execute.
电脑本身不会做任何事情 它只能执行一些简单的指令
And to make a program do something useful we need to put those instructions together in a way that it does what we want.
为了让程序做一些有用的东西 我们需要把那些指令以特殊的方式结合在一起
So we can turn the computer into a web browser, into a server, into a game-playing machine, into a toaster, without anywhere to put the bread.
我们可以把电脑变成网页浏览器、服务器、游戏机、面包机 (没有地方放面包)
But it can do anything we can imagine: at least any computation we want to do.
它能做我们想到的任何东西 至少是任何的运算
The power of the computer is that it can execute the steps super super fast.
电脑的长处是它可以运行的非常非常快速
So we can execute billions of instructions in one second.
这样我们就可以在一秒钟执行上亿个指令
The program gives us a way to tell the computer what steps to take.
程序告诉电脑去做什么步骤
So there are many different languages for programming computers.
所以有许多不同的编程语言
The language we are going to learn in this course is the language called Python, like the snake. It is also named after Monty Python.
在这个课程里我们学习的语言叫做 Python 就像条蛇的名字 它是以 Monty Python 命名的
The important thing about Python is that it gives us a nice high-level language that we can use to write programs.
Python 的好处是它是一个高级的语言
And that means instead of our program running directly on the computer, the programs we write will be an input to the Python program which runs on the computer.
这意味着我们的程序会被编成一个 Python 程序之后在电脑运行 而不是直接在电脑运行
What Python is is called an interpreter. That means it runs our programs, it interprets them,
Python 被称为一个解释程序 这说明它会运行我们的程序 解释它们
executes the programs that we wrote in Python language by running a program in a language into the computer can understand directly.
用电脑懂的语言执行我们用 Python 语言写的程序